Clinton Hays

Ilsan, South Korea | 010-2038-9670 | rhiannon.clintkorea@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Early childhood educator focusing on teaching English as a second language. Five years of experience in South Korea teaching a range of ages from kindergarten to adult. Organized and professional demeanor with a passion for classroom management and childhood development.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Mar. 2020 - Current

Foreign ESL Educator, Winny English Education, Ilsan

- Lead classes focused on speaking, reading, and writing
- Design and implement lesson plans, core curriculum, and classroom management techniques
- Structure and lead speech contests, singing contests, and seasonal activities
- Create testing rubrics and administer progress tests
- Provide student progress updates to co-teacher and parents

Mar. 2018 - Mar. 2020

Foreign ESL Educator, Ellin Nature Kindergarten, Ilsan

- Taught English speaking, reading, writing, and math to kindergarten students
- Specialized in English learning through drama practice and science based activities
- Designed activities, lesson plans, contests, and field trips for students
- Managed classroom environment and behavior
- Communicated student progress to parents

Dec. 2015 - Feb. 2018

Foreign ESL Educator, GnB English Academy, Masan

- Taught English conversation, grammar, and writing to K-12 and adult students
- Designed activities, lesson plans, and speaking contests for students
- Prepared students for national assessment tests
- Monitored and managed student learning and behavior
- Communicated student progress to parents and co-teachers
- Responsible for 40+ classes per week

EDUCATION

2009

University of Central Oklahoma, Bachelor of Arts: English - Creative Writing

learnTEFL 150 Tefl/Tesol Certification